Guide to the Paul Fishbeck menu collection, 1955-2015
Fishbeck, Paul menu collection
- Maxwell’s Plum in New York City, postcards (Box 1, Folder 8)
  Notes from the collector: Must be thirty to forty years old.
- Clyde’s in Washington D.C. area (Box 1, Folder 8)
  Notes from the collector: I first went to Clyde’s over thirty years with my cousin’s son for breakfast. It was the only one then. Now is a well established chain of high quality food and run I believe by a hotelie. The last time we went to the “original’ in Georgetown with a couple of fraternity brothers there was a bomb scare on the street and we were evacuated. The fact one of them was the first US Ambassador to Albania wasn’t a consideration I guess?
- Bouchon in Napa Valley. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  Notes from the collector: One of Thomas Keller’s properties and just down the road from his landmark restaurant. Obviously not everyone can afford to eat at the later so he saw an opening for “reasonable” prices in Bouchon. Our only complaint was the fact the tables were on top of each other and getting up was a real challenge. The menu covered all the bases one would expect from such a professional. We went there say three or four years ago with an old friend.
- Whispering Vines Cafe, 2013 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  Notes from the collector: A local property. Reasonable prices in a pleasant spot in a winery on the Mornington Peninsula. Most of the restaurants down here are way overpriced and attract the visitors and not the locals. Good idea on the wine - have half glass of each. For children - call them little people rather than children.
- Hotel du Lac Coppet (Box 1, Folder 9)
  Notes from the collector: Although not a menu the brochure gives an indication of the style of food and the ambiance of the property. We stayed here by chance and when we checked out of our four-hundred-year-old room I noticed a brochure on the desk for the taking. It was our introduction to the Relais and Chateaux chain of great properties around the world. Stayed in the late seventies from memory.
- Wayside Inn brochures (Box 1, Folder 9)
  Notes from the collector: Described previously.
- Cape Cod Room in Chicago (Box 1, Folder 9)
  Notes from the collector: In its day, probably the best restaurant in Chicago. No menu, but freshness was their secret. From memory, all seafood flown in daily from either coast.
- Hoefly’s in Long Beach, California (Box 1, Folder 9)
  Notes from the collector: Around the late fifties or early sixties. Everything on the men to please everyone. Coffee – 15 cents! Cocktails not priced - Why? Signed by the owner for friends of ours we met on the ship.
- Grison’s Chicken House in San Francisco, ca. 1962 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  Notes from the collector: Probably early sixties when we lived there. Pretty ordinary to change some prices with a pen, but maybe they were being clever, as the prices went down, not up! Recommended by various guides, including Duncan Hines, who was the guru when I was young.
- Bahnhof Buffet, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  Notes from the collector: amazing operation. There were some eight or more places to eat in the “basement” of the Berne railway station. There was what was really a small hotel underground for the staff only – some thirty to forty rooms. The owner, Fritz Haller gave us a tour. French and German would have covered most of the customers, and prices need some calculating.
- Bentleigh’s, ca. 1962 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  Notes from the collector: Maybe Oakland, California. The menu is supposed to show elegance.
- Baron’s Table, Holiday Inn in Hong Kong, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  Notes from the collector: Very well-thought-out menu in German. Print very small. Prices in Hong Kong dollars from memory. About ten to one?
- The Chocolate Fish, Wellington, New Zealand, 2014 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  Notes from the collector: Four of us had four sandwiches, one each, and one bottle of wine –$100!! But it was a fun place. There was a small dining room, but as the sun was shining everyone ate outside. They had a huge lawn where most people sat on the grass! This might not work in North America, but New Zealanders are pretty tough. Right on the harbor, so a perfect position in good weather.
- Moorooduc Estate, Mornington Peninsula, Melbourne, Australia, 2012 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  Notes from the collector: This was a club dinner. I used to belong but thought ten years was enough. Priced around $50-60. The great thing about functions if that you know exactly what to plan and especially if it is a fixed contract. Note there was no choice of the main course which is somewhat unusual.
- Ciao Bella, 2013 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  Notes from the collector: The menu explains itself. With the full menu on the blackboard.
- Holiday Inn, Hong Kong, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  Notes from the collector: We stayed in the Holiday Inn (American), dined in the Main restaurant (German) in an Asian city. I think the price in US dollars, was say $10. Very expensive menu cover, but could be used for other events.
- Hofbrauhaus, Munnich, Germany, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  Notes from the collector: At that time probably the most famous restaurant in Munich. I think it sat about one thousand customers. The changed in the menu handwritten show they are confident in their operation and the menu covers a multitude of dishes. So why change menus for the sake of fussy customers.
- Dining Experience, SS Dawn Princess (Box 1, Folder 10)
  Notes from the collector: Dining experience – although not a menu it highlights the breakdown of the kitchen staff required to prepare about ten thousand meals each and every day at sea. Who else can afford a full time ice carver! Both of the pictured gentlemen on the cover attended either a hotel or catering school. Most have done so in Italy and both have been with Princess for a long period of time saying something about the company! Each voyage they put on a cooking demonstration which is part education and part entertainment.
- Wildwood Inn, Paradise California (Box 1, Folder 10)
  Notes from the collector: It is noted the year was 1963 but not certain. I was manager of a nearby hotel and probably went there around that time. Note the steaks were not cheap for that time, but other items relatively cheaper. Lots of info on the menu confusing those who only wanted to order a meal. “Minimum service charge for small children” How many would you like?
- SS Dawn Princess Menus, 2014 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  Notes from the collector: A full set of menus from our recent trip to New Zealand and return to Melbourne. The easy way to travel. The voyage, to use maritime language, was for thirteen nights. The ship makes about six or seven exact same voyages each summer. So the menus are exactly the same each time. This system has numerous advantages as you can imagine. The main galley prepares some nine to ten thousand meals each day. In the information sheets I sent some time ago the ship told the number of staff involved in the preparation of meals. With computers the number of each item served can be recorded exactly making ordering much more precise than in the old days. Percentages of each item ordered can be used for further purchases using the entire summer voyages as a guideline. Nowadays a ship turns around in about ten hours so everything has to be delivered and stored to a strict schedule. Thus many of the staff have to work harder while in port than at sea. I recall the ships I served on had two or three days in San Francisco to take on goods for the next voyage. The new provisions for our latest voyage would have been loaded in Melbourne where everything would have been available and goods would be of a high standard determined by shore visits to the various providers. The only item I saw being taken aboard on the cruise was fuel in Auckland, New Zealand.
  The menus – The clue for each night is at the bottom of the page with Italian Night, English Night, etc. etc. It seemed to be the Head Waiter’s job to see the waiters used the correct ones for the particular night. The menus are well balanced with three appetizers, four soups and salads, and six or so main courses. No one went hungry. The mains included a pasta, a vegetarian, a fish or seafood, and one or two red meat and or a poultry dish. Some dishes used to be flambéed at the table as did desserts, but with current concerns this has been done away with. And if there is nothing to one’s liking for the night, then one can always choose one, or two or three of the items on the left hand side of the menu. After the three courses, one is presented with a dessert menu which again offers many choices and old regulars. We often just asked for ice cream, which of course, changed daily and was entirely made on the ship, I never noticed many passengers ordering any of drinks on the left hand side of the dessert menu. There was a comprehensive wine list in addition to the above mentioned.. In order to please light drinkers, one could have just one glass and the waiter would mark the bottle and one could have more the next night.
  Everyone on the staff tried their best to please and if one didn’t want, say Brussels sprouts, then one could ask for something else. I don’t think menus have changed much over the years except perhaps healthier, smaller portions, but not too small, and notices to warn of eating undercooked items and reference to allergies and diet requests.
  The dining room had separate breakfast and lunch menus of a much simpler style, but still with daily specials. In case one couldn’t wait for the dining room to open there was always the buffet which had everything anyone could want and was open about eighteen hours each day. In addition there was a restaurant which served only pizzas and also a steakhouse open for evening meals at a slight extra charge. If getting from one’s stateroom to the dining room proved too difficult there was always room service, twenty-four hours a day.
  The main dining rooms had two sittings for dinner – the first about 5:45 and the second about 7:45. Now there is a trend to have open seating from say 5 PM to 10 PM which allows to dine when the please more or less. We first came across this on a Norwegian Line Ship and it worked well. If one went to the dining room and your preference was not available, you were given a beeper and when a table was available they gave you a buzz. Usually only five or ten minutes. No problem since you weren’t going anywhere.
- U.K. Menus, 2014 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  Notes from the collector: Friends of ours recently went touring in the U. K. and they asked what they could bring back. I said menus of course, and told them where they would end up. They brought several from quaint pubs and inns. …hamburger in every shape and form seems to take over the market over there. And most places seem to be very concerned the customer doesn’t sue for any breach of nutrition. Our friends had Chinese takeaway one night and were asked if they wanted chips and gravy (commercial) with the food. All very exciting.
  Menus include: Emirates Airlines, Best Pizza and Kebab House, The Boat Inn, The Buccleuch Hotel and Restaurant, The Famous Star Hotel, Dumfriesshire, The Fox and Pheasant Inn, Cumbria, Marston’s Inns and Taverns, Nith Hotel, Dumfries, Old Success Inn, The Roebuck Pub and Dining Room, The Sycamore Tree, Longtown, Trees Café, Wheeler’s of St. James, Dunfries, Scotland.
- Victoria Australia Menus, 2014 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  Notes from the collector: When I started this journey I thought I was sending pieces of paper or cardboard with words written or drawn on them. I didn’t know how I even obtained many of the menus let alone when or where. And I only had some idea of the dates. Only since I have been obtaining them more recently have I realized it is about people rather than paper. When I ask for a copy of the restaurant’s menu I get some very interesting replies – too busy, okay if the boss isn’t looking, why do I want it, etc. When I have the chance to tell someone where it is going the response can be completely different. For example -
  Late last year Barnie and I went to a small town for a few nights. There was an Accor resort in the town of Creswick, just out of Ballarat, one of our provincial cities. Good mining country and find the area fascinating. Ballarat even had a stock exchange during the gold rush days. One night we ate at the American Hotel, and had quite a reasonable meal for a country pub. After the meal I asked the manager if I could have a copy of his menu and told him where it would end up. He got quite excited and said to hold on a minute. He gathered all his menus. He was a hometown boy and had never heard of Cornell. Told him about the Ivy League and had heard of Harvard! He asked if we would like to see the rest of the property.
  There were guest bedrooms, a function room, and more. He even pointed out the outbuilding where the gold was held before being shipped to Melbourne. The rooms were covered with prints of Norman Lindsay, a hometown boy. Originals would be worth a fortune as he was very successful. The two original American owners were involved with Cobb and Co. a stagecoach company which covered the east coast of Australia and a cinema company. The town of Creswick had seen better times since the gold rush days, but now a very successful woolen mill with a retail outlet and a great patisserie on the main street. The passenger rail has been brought back top life for a couple of times each week.
  We just spent four days in what is called the High Country some one and fifty miles north east of Melbourne. We ate in four different restaurants and found them all satisfactory and a lot of fun. Menus as follows-
  The Bright Brewery. A good concept. You order and pay at the counter. You get your own silver from a bucket. The food is delivered to your table. Outside tables when the weather permits.
  Alpine Hotel. A bustling property. Same concept as the Brewery. A bit of everything on the menu. Even Moet at $110.00. Established 1864.
  Tahbilk Restaurant in the Tahbilk Winery. This is a favorite of ours, only about sixty miles north of Melbourne on the Goulbourn River. It is the oldest winery in Victoria and some of the oldest vines of a particular variety in the world! We have been going to this winery for about forty-five years now and pick up a couple of cases each time. The menu is several sheets, but I grabbed the main one.
- Doyles, 2014 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  Notes from the collector: The setting would be hard to beat. We went there on a weekend and it was packed. Around since 1885 which is ancient for Australia. The daily menu is stappled to the history so there is no wastage. I believe the cooking oil is changed every day rather than strained and reused. A time and motion study exercise. The prices are not cheap, but freshness comes with a cost. A great operation going strong. A surcharge to be the labor costs on weekends.
- Itali.co, 2015 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  Notes from the collector: A very good true Italian restaurant down the cost from our abode. And not too expensive for the quality. I usually sit so I can watch the people in the open kitchen and one can tell everything is made to order. A surcharge applies on public holidays because of our crazy wage structure. The owner brings out young staff from Italy and provided accommodation so they can get a feel for our culture. And they all seem happy. the restaurant is in one half of an old hotel which is good for for both parties.
- Portsea Hotel (Box 1, Folder 14)
  Notes from the collector: A very old hotel at the end of the road on the Peninsula. Sweeping views of the Bay, outdoor dining and atmosphere. One orders at the counter, but the food is delivered to the table. I couldn’t grab the full menu. Been going there for almost fifty years. Some very good meals, some ordinary depending what is the day of the week. Always can be a problem with different staff on different days.
- Le Bouchon, 2015 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  Notes from the collector: A true French Restaurant in the closest town. Reasonable for the quality served. Small and rather noisy, but not pretending to be anything more than a French bistro. The town. or better village, now has two pizza come Italian, one Chinese, one pub, one Asian, and a bakery serving meals. Quite a choice.
- Lord Chumley’s (Box 1, Folder 14)
  Notes from the collector: Finally. one owned by a fraternity brother, Don Clark’54 who was always in the hospitality business. Think it was in the 70’s on a visit to DisneyWorld. Note other locations mentioned. Have to be pretty confident customers like this one. Menu slides into a very flash jacket embossed in gold. Don was talking about Key Man insurance the day I met him. Fairly new concept I recall. Interesting wine list.
- Cunard, Queen Elizabeth, 2015 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  Notes from the collector: An old friend of ours, the widow of a previous Director of ASIO, one of our intelligence agencies, went on a voyage last summer and kindly brought back several different menus from the ship. The best two are the first and last night’s menus cleverly included in a booklet about the history of the company. You will note at the top is a Royal Spa Selection and I had no idea what the figures next to the item meant until I wised up and looked down below to see they were calories/fat/fibre! Someone said no one goes on a voyage to worry about the diet, but there will be a percentage who do nowadays. First time I have seen such figures. The Cunard ships are class ships and what level of cabin one has determines which dining room one dines in. Our friend was one step down from the top. If you look at the menus carefully you will see they lean toward being American. Main courses are entrees and many items will be familiar to Americans. As an excursion in our senior year took the class on the Queen Mary we toured the galley, but failed to provide us with any menus! The Queen Mary is now a floating hotel in Long Beach, California.
- Nickodell, Undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
  Notes from the collector: A very busy menu when restaurants tried to cover all the bases. I have no idea if I ever went there or someone gave it to me, but looked like the sixties, but there is a 77 at bottom of first page. Enough salads alone to sink a ship. Mentioning air conditioning and “free Parking” are interesting. Three cheers for Hollywood!.
- The Menzies Hotel, Sydney, Australia, 2015 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  Notes from the collector: Room Service menu with 1963 on the cover – the year the hotel opened. We didn’t dine in any official restaurant due to my condition so this had to do. Note kid’s menu being very reasonable and wine the same, except Tattinger Champagne.
- The Vibe, Melbourne, Australia, 2015 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  Notes from the collector: Another room service menu for comparison. Minimum order required and a $4 charge for delivery. What about picking it up yourself? Steak not cheap or wines. Only one Victoria wine and Knappstein from outer space! Not a flash hotel but only across the street from the train station where we caught the train to Sydney.
- Cafe Menu Trainlink, 2015 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  Notes from the collector: Speaking of trains, this is the menu for on board consumption. There are no sit down dining rooms on the east coast trains that I know of, but at least one can get a decent sandwich,main meal,glass of wine or a beer. And headache and pain relief materials.
- King "Neptune's Table", Undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Kook-o-theek, Holland, Undated (Box 1, Folder 15)